# **VIVIAN LIU**

 ¶ Toronto, ON | ¬ www.vivianliudesign.com | ™ vivian.liu67@gmail.com

## **SUMMARY**

Multidisciplinary designer and lifelong learner, crafting human-centered experiences at Ginkgo Health which led to the **successful launch of our first app**. Passionate about problem solving and designing products that are functional, inclusive, and create a sense of belonging.

# **EXPERIENCE**

# **UI/UX Lead Designer**

Ginkgo Health (Full Time) | Vancouver, BC | June 2023 - Current

- Took ownership of projects, including subscription-based monetization and shared family accounts.
- Collaborated with business and dev teams using Agile methodology to gather requirements, rapidly iterate, and lead design demos, while mentoring a junior designer.
- Solved ambiguous problems when pivoting business strategies with empathy for end users, harnessing motivation theories and design methodologies to push for better UX.
- Analyzed 300+ entries of user feedback data to inform user-centered design decisions, enhance user experience, and meet business expectations.
- Created our first design system on Figma to streamline the design process.

## **UI/UX Designer**

Ginkgo Health (Contractor) | Vancouver, BC | Sept 2022 - June 2023

- Designed intuitive, accessible UI/UX for a senior audience, transforming a complex health assessment into easily digestible experiences for a frictionless onboarding process.
- Collaborated with stakeholders to create a compelling story for the product using UX and business strategy.
- Conducted user research to learn their business context, decision-making process, and create personas.

# Marketing & Design Associate

UW Food Services (Co-op) | Waterloo, ON | Sept 2018 - Dec 2018

- Designed a new department website, improving user experience, and conducted user research through student focus groups and surveys to align with market trends and customer expectations.
- Designed marketing materials for new products, menus, and the launch of a new mobile ordering app.

## **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor of Mathematics, Math & Business Administration**

University of Waterloo | 2021

Certifications: Visual and Interface Design, User Experience Design

## SKILLS

Figma, Adobe Suite, User-Centered Design, Wireframe and Prototyping, User Research and Analysis, Market Research and Analysis, Journey Mapping, Affinity Mapping, Interactive Design, Copywriting, Content Strategy, Office Suite, HTML/CSS